어떤 크루즈를 타신다고요?
So what kind of cruise
is this you're going on?
'본 어게인' 크루즈란다
It's called
the Born Again Boat Ride.
크리스찬 잡지에서
최고 점수를 받았어
Christian Quarterly gave
it their highest rating--
가시관 5개
five thorny crowns.
너도 같이 가면 좋겠구나
I do wish you'd
come with me, Sheldon.
만약 제가 간다면
하느님이 기적을 일으킨다는
Well, Mom, if I did, it
would be conclusive proof
결정적인 증거가 될 거에요
that your God
can work miracles.
너만 아쉬울 걸
You're missing out.
정말 재밌을텐데
It's gonna
be wall-to-wall fun.
테마도 다양해
It's all themed.
요나와 고래 구경하기
There's Jonah
and the Whale Watching.
최후의 만찬 뷔페
All-you-can-eat
Last Supper Buffet.
내가 제일 좋아하는
'신과 함께 쏴라'도 있어
And my personal favorite,
Gunning with God.
'신과 함께 쏴라'는 뭔가요?
What's Gunning with God?
I'm afraid to ask.
들으면 빵 터질 거야
Oh, it is a hoot
and a half.
자신의 죄를 찰흙 비둘기에 적고
You write your sins
on a clay pigeon,
공중에 날려서
가루로 만드는 거야
they fire 'em up in the air,
and you pulverize them
12 게이지 엽총으로
with a 12-gauge shotgun
주님의 자비로 가득하단다
full of our Lord's
forgiveness.
그래도 지난 번에 비해
훨씬 발전하셨네요
Frankly, Mom, I'm encouraged
to see how advanced
your group has become--
willing to sail out
지구 끝으로 떨어질까봐
바다는 두려워할 줄 알았는데
into the ocean without fear
of falling off the edge.
예를 들어
MARY:
For example,
쉘리도 배에 탔다면
if Shelly was aboard,
he'd write,
비둘기에 '말대꾸'라고 적겠지
"Smart mouth"
on his pigeon,
그리고 빵!
and then bam!
주님께서 주시고
주님께서 날려 버리시네요
The Lord giveth and
the Lord bloweth away.
Well, Mom,
이번 주말 일정표를 짰는데
according to my itinerary
for our weekend together,
후라이드 치킨부터 시작이에요
the fun begins with
fried chicken.
맛있겠네
엄마가 써야 할
요리 재료는 다 준비했어요
너도 좋아할 거야
You are in for a treat.
엄마가 만든
후라이드 치킨 때문에
My mother's fried chicken
아빠를 특대 사이즈 관에
넣어야 했어
is why we had to buy my dad
the extra large coffin.
방금 도착해서 피곤하실텐데
Sheldon, she just
got off the plane.
요리할 생각 없으실걸
She doesn't want to cook.
물론 있지
Of course she does.
엄마가 요리하는 건
사랑의 표현이야
Making me food is her way
of saying "I love you""
피곤할 때도 요리하는 건
Making me food when
she's too tired to cook
날 정말 사랑한다는 뜻이지
is her way of saying
"I really love you."
오랜만에 외식도 괜찮지 않니
Actually, I wouldn't mind going
out for a bite, Sheldon.
그럼 배부르지 않을까요?
Won't that spoil our appetites
이따가 치킨도 먹어햐 하는데
for the chicken you're
going to make me?
나가서 먹어요,
스시 좋아하세요?
All right, that settles it, we're
going out. Do you like sushi?
근처에 괜찮은 식당이 있어요
There's a great little
place down the street.
먹어본 적은 없지만
I've never had it,
but there's no harm in
새로운 도전도 나쁘지 않지
trying something new.
새로운 건 위험해요
There's a lot of harm
in trying something new.
그러니까 약이랑 화장품을
토끼에 실험하잖아요
That's why we test out
drugs and cosmetics
on bunny rabbits.
쉘든, 미친 사람처럼
떠들고 있어
Sheldon, you're talking
like a crazy person.
어렸을 때 검사한 적 있어
Actually, I had him
tested as a child.
의사가 괜찮다네
Doctor says he's fine.
거봐
Told you.
휴스턴에 있는 전문의한테
안 가서 조금 후회되긴 해
Although, I do regret
not following up
with that specialist in Houston.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
DC 기타 미국드라마 갤러리
The Big Bang Theory 5x06
The Rhinitis Revelation
Original Air Date on October 20, 2011
자막 공대언니
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Irasshaimase!
소리 지르지 마요
Stop yelling!
전혀 마음에 들지 않아
I'm not happy about this.
네 마음에 드는 게 있기나 해?
What's the last thing
you were ever happy about?
후라이드 치킨
The prospect
of fried chicken.
정말 신난다
This is exciting.
내가 알던 곳에도
스시가 있었는데
Back home, the diner on
Route Four serves sushi,
피시 스틱 몇 조각에
사이드로 밥이 나왔지
but it's just cut up fish sticks
and a side of Uncle Ben's.
메뉴에 쿵푸 폰트로 적혀있지만
They put it on the menu
in those kung fu letters,
but that don't make it sushi.
그렇다고 스시는 아니지
쿵푸 폰트라 하는 건
조금 차별적이네요
Uh, kung fu letters might
not be politically correct.
'칭총'만 피하면 되는 줄 알았지
Oh, I thought the one we
couldn't say was "ching chong""
그것도 그래요
Yeah, yeah, that, too.
에이미랑은 잘 지내고 있니?
So, Shelly, what's up
with you and your friend Amy,
엄마도 좀 캐묻고 싶구나
if you don't mind
a mother prying a bit?
에이미에 관련된
소식이 있어요
Well, there's actually
big news on the Amy front.
하등동물의 중독에 대한
신경생물학 연구 중인데
She's been studying the
neurobiology of addiction
in lower animals.
불가사리를 코카인에
중독시키는데 거의 성공했어요
She's this close to getting
a starfish hooked on cocaine.
둘이 어떤 사이인지 알고 있니?
Do you have any idea what's
going on with those two?
네스호 괴물이랑 비슷하죠
It's kind of like
the Loch Ness monster.
실제로 있는 건지 아닌지
Maybe there's something
there, maybe there isn't.
우리는 알 수 없어요
We'll probably never know.
그래도 생각만으로
꽤나 즐겁게 해주네요
But sometimes it's fun to creep
yourself out thinking about it.
네 연애는 잘 돼 가니?
How are you doing on
the young lady front?
장거리 연애 중이라 들었는데
I hear you're in some sort
of a long distance situation?
네, 라지 동생이에요
Yeah, it's Raj's sister.
조금 힘들죠
It's kind of tough.
여자친구는 인도에 있고
She's in India.
걔네 부모님은 백인이랑
사귄다는 걸 반기지 않아요
Also, her parents aren't happy
she's dating someone white.
재밌는 관점이네
Oh, that's funny
turn, isn't it?
그렇게 반대로 생각할 수 있구나
You never think about it
going the other way.
억지로 지속하지는 마
Well, you can't force things.
실제로 감정이 있는 건지
You need to figure out if
you're in a relationship
끼워 맞추는 건지
생각할 필요가 있어
or if you're just
calling it one.
말을 물가에
끌고 갈 수는 있어도
It's like they say--
a cat can have kittens
억지로 물을 먹일 수는 없다
in the oven but that
don't make 'em biscuits.
이런 속담도 있잖아요
And that reminds me
of another saying.
닭을 식용유에
끌고 갈 수는 있어도
You can lead a chicken
to Crisco, but you can't
억지로 엄마한테
요리를 시킬 수는 없다
make your mother fry it.
또 치킨 얘기 꺼내기만 해
Sheldon, you pester me one
more time about chicken,
여기서 바로 니킥을 날릴테니
I will put you over my knee
right here in this restaurant.
날 위해 한 번만 더 얘기해
Please pester her.
Please, for me.
스시는 괜찮았나요?
So, Mrs. Cooper, what did
you think of the sushi?
좋았어
It was good.
조금 더 맛있을 수도 있었어
The only thing that would
have made it better
익혔더라면
is if it was cooked
소고기였다면 더 좋았겠지
and if it was beef.
쉘든, 엘레베이터는
언제 고친다니?
Sheldon, when is your landlord
going to fix the elevator?
몰라요
I don't know.
최근에는 미사일 격납고로
바꿀 계획도 세웠어요
Lately we've been talking about
converting it
into a missile silo.
버뱅크에 선제 공격을
해야 한다고 생각하나 봐요
Your son seems to think
we need to launch
a preemptive strike on Burbank.
당하기 전에 물리쳐야지
Get them before
they get us.
어이, 드디어 나타났네
Hey, look who decided
to show up.
라지, 뭐하고 있어?
Raj, what are you doing?
너네를 못 찾아서
새 친구 6명을 사귀었어
I couldn't find you guys
so I bought six new friends.
슬프지만 셋은 죽었지
Three, sadly, are dead.
엄마, 라지 기억하지?
Mom, you
remember Rajesh?
라지, 우리 엄마야
- Rajesh, my mother.
- Of course.
또 만나서 반가워요
Mrs. Cooper.
So nice to see you again.
그래, 나도 반가워
Well, it's so nice
to see you, too.
술 문제로 속 썩이는 건
I thought it was
our Indians
우리 쪽 인디언 아니였니?
that had the occasional
alcohol problem.
그렇게 말씀하시면 안돼요
We don't say that, either.
리스트 정리해서 드릴게요
I'll make you a list.
역시 백인이 최고야
Oh, that would be mighty
white of you.
어떤 아픔이 있길래
So, Raj, what pain
are you trying
술을 그렇게 마신 거니?
to cover up with alcohol?
- 전 괜찮아요
- 정말?
- Nothing, I'm fine.
- Are ya?
아뇨
(sobbing)
No.
그래
That's better.
뭐가 문제인지 말해보렴
Now tell me what's
bothering you.
너무 외로워요
I'm so lonely.
혼자 태어나고 혼자 죽는 거야
Oh, yes, born alone,
die alone.
사람이란 다 그래
It's a tragic
human condition.
자, 라지
Now, Raj,
엄마는 바빠서 가봐야 해
if you'll excuse my mother,
피칸 파이를 만들 건데
she's about to make a pecan pie
너무 맛있어서
만회할 수 있을 거야
that'll be so good
I'll almost forget
후라이드 치킨은 놓쳤거든
how she blew it
with the fried chicken.
쉘든, 네 친구가 아파하고 있어
Sheldon, your
friend is hurtin'.
누군가 아파할 때는
어떻게 해야하지?
What do we do when
someone's hurtin'?
따뜻한 음료를 권해야죠
Offer them a hot beverage.
미친 듯이 취했을 때는
And when they're
drunk as a skunk,
어떤 음료를 권해야 하지?
what beverage
do we offer?
커피요
Coffee.
그리고 어떻게 해야 한다고?
And what do we do it with?
자, 내 말 들어
Now you listen to me.
아직 인연을 못 만났어도
I know you feel like
you can't find someone,
짚신도 짝이 있다잖니
but there's a
lock for every key.
내가 아는 여자가 있는데
Back home, there's a girl
월마트에서 일하고
키가 무지 커
works at the Wal-Mart.
Tall, tall girl.
갈퀴로 거위 사냥 할 기세야
Woman could hunt
geese with a rake.
평생 혼자 지낼 줄 알았지
Thought she'd never
find a man, then one day,
wouldn't ya know,
그러던 어느 날
묘기 농구단 '할렘'이 방문했지
Harlem Globetrotters
come to town.
줄여 말하면
Long story short,
세미프로 농구 선수랑
today that woman
travels the world
혼혈 아이 둘을 낳고
with a semi-professional
basketball player
세계를 여행하고 있단다
and two beautiful
mixed-race babies.
사투리 때문에
알아듣지 못 했어요
I didn't get a lot of that
because of your accent,
그래도 말투가 위안이 되네요
but the general tone
was soothing
기분이 나아졌어요
and somehow I feel better.
피칸 파이 못 먹겠지?
I'm not going to get
my pecan pie, am I?
오레오라도 먹을래?
You want some Oreos?
- 더블 크림?
- 아니, 일반이야
- Double Stuf?
- No, regular.
그래, 날 두 번 죽여라
Nice. Kick a man when he's down.
드디어 뭔가 같이 하네요
I'm glad we're finally getting
to do something together,
둘만의 시간이 필요했어요
just the two of us.
그래, 휴가 때는 빨래가
더욱 하고 싶더구나
Sure. One thing you really
miss when you're on
vacation is laundry.
다우니 너무 많이 쓰지 마세요
*다우니 : 섬유유연제
Careful, you're using
too much Downey.
옷이 너무 부드러우면
잠 오는 거 아시잖아요
You know if my clothes get
too soft it makes me sleepy.
옛날 생각 나네
Well, this takes me back.
난 빨래하고
넌 옆에서 잔소리하고
Me doing your laundry, you
next to me criticizing.
좋네요
It is nice, isn't it?
어머님
Mrs. Cooper.
- Hi!
- Oh, hello, darlin'.
쉘든, 왜 얘기 안 해줬어
Sheldon, you didn't tell
me your mom was coming.
매주 보내는 이메일에 썼잖아
It was in my weekly
e-mail blast.
'사탕무의 계절이 왔다'랑
Right between
"Beet season is finally here"
'사탕무로 인한 붉은색 대변을
대장암으로 오해' 사이에 적었어
and "Uh-oh, red stool from
beets leads to cancer scare."
어떻게 지냈니?
So, how've you been?
좋아요
Good, good.
레너드한테
새 여자가 있다는데
I hear that Leonard
has a new girlfriend.
넌 괜찮아?
How are you doing
with all that?
네, 헤어진 지 좀 되서
Oh, fine. You know,
it's been a while.
저도 새로운 사람 만나려고요
I'm getting
back out there.
새로운 만남을 가질 때
Let me ask you, when
you get back out there,
혹시 이걸 입을 거니?
are you wearing this?
입으면 정말 귀여워요
Well, it's super cute on.
공짜 음료로
옷의 10배는 벌었어요
That top has paid for itself
in free drinks like ten
times what it cost.
페니는 그런 쪽으로
미래가 밝아요
Yes, Penny has a lot
of her money tied up
in promiscuity futures.
얘야
Hon, you think
남자랑 꾸준한 만남이
어려운 이유는 생각해봤니?
maybe the reason why
you're having trouble
finding a guy
to settle down with
롤러코스터를 표도 없이
타게 해서 그런 거 아냐?
is because you're letting them
ride the roller coaster
without buying a ticket?
항상 롤러코스터를
타는 건 아니에요
Oh, they don't always get
to ride the roller coaster.
어떤 때는 티컵만
돌리고 끝나요
Sometimes they only get
to spin the teacups.
오늘 밤에 놀러 나가는데
Now I'm going out tonight.
Would it be crazy
패션 조언 좀 부탁해도 될까요?
to ask you to look at the
outfit I'm going to wear?
물론이지
Oh, not crazy at all.
그리고 너무 자책하지 마
And don't beat yourself up.
네 나이 때는 그렇지
When I was your age, you could
have me for a car ride
나도 누가 차 태워주고
딸기 와인만 있으면 충분하더라
and a bottle
of strawberry wine.
이번 주 이메일 소식지에는
빼야할 내용이군
That will not be
in this week's e-mail blast.
이번 봄에
국제우주정거장에 가게 됐어요
So, this spring,
I get to go
to the International
Space Station.
우주로 떠나는구나
Oh, my word,
a trip to the heavens.
영원히 거주할 생각이면
If you ever want
to live there eternally,
좋은 책 추천해줄 수 있는데
I've got a good book
you could read.
'찰리 브라운 크리스마스'를
매년 봐서
Thanks, but I watch the
Charlie Brown Christmas special
내용은 대충 알아요
every year, so I get the gist.
엄마가 자랑스러워하겠네
I bet your mom
is really proud of you.
아뇨
Nope.
제가 포기하지 않으면
She says if I don't back out
단식 투쟁을 하실 거래요
she's going to go
on a hunger strike.
위험하기 전까지
몇 년이 걸리겠지만
It would take years before
she'd be in any kind of danger,
but still.
내일 특별한 일정을 준비했어요
I've got a treat
for us tomorrow, Mom.
노벨 수상자 사울 펄무터의
우주론 강연에 데리고 갈게요
I'm taking you
to see Saul Perlmutter
give a lecture
about his Nobel Prize-winning
work in cosmology.
Q&A가 제일 기대되요
And the best part is,
at the Q and A afterward,
답하기 어려운
질문을 몇 개 생각했어요
I've worked up
a couple of "Q's"
that will stump
his sorry "A."
쉘리, 그러지 말고
I don't know, Shelly.
관광하면 어떨까?
I thought we could do
a little sightseeing.
아들이 노벨 수상자를
망신 시키는 것보다
What sight is better
than your little boy
더 좋은 볼거리가 있어요?
embarrassing a Nobel laureate?
그래, 쉘든
Come on, Sheldon,
we'll take your mom
할리우드 사인을 보러 가고
to see the Hollywood sign,
왁스 뮤지엄, 명성의 거리
the wax museum,
the Walk of Fame.
로데오 거리도 좋겠다
Ooh, maybe
a little Rodeo Drive.
핸드백에 $12,000는 못 쓰지만
Well, I can't spend
$12,000 on a handbag,
그런 이들을 비난의 시선으로
바라보는 건 공짜잖아
but it's free
to look upon those
who do with righteous
condemnation.
어때?
What do you say?
어떠냐고
What do I say?
우리 일정을 더 이상
망치지 말라고
I say you people need
to stop ruining my mom's visit
스시도 그렇고,
우울증이며 야한 셔츠며
with your sushi, and your
sadness and your slutty shirts.
그만해
Stop it.
네 셔츠 얘기가 아냐
He's not talking about your
shirt. Your shirt is fine.
정말 맛있다
These are delicious.
팬케익 맛을 내는 건
베이컨 기름이야
The trick to pancakes
is bacon grease.
난 모든 요리에 그걸 써
I cook everything in it.
모든 요리요?
건강에 안 좋잖아요
Everything? Aren't you
worried about your health?
의사 놈들은 매번
말을 바꾸잖아
Oh, doctors are always
changing their mind.
이번 주에는
베이컨 기름이 나빠다 해도
One week bacon grease
is bad for you.
다음 주에는
더 섭취하라고 난리야
The next week we're not
getting enough of it.
잘 잤니, 쉘리
Good morning, Shelly.
엄마, 어젯밤은 제가 잘못했어요
Mom, I want to apologize
for my behavior last night.
괜찮아
- Apology accepted.
- Great.
엄마도 펄무터 강연
좋아하실 거에요
Now, you're going to love
the Perlmutter lecture.
우주의 나이가
6천년보다 많다고 할 때
Look, he will be stating
that the universe is older
than 6,000 years,
but I thought
엄마는 손으로 귀를 막고
you could stick your
fingers in your ears
'어메이징 그레이스'를
흥얼거리면 좋겠어요
and hum "Amazing Grace"
during those parts.
네 친구들이랑 나간다고 했잖니
I am still going out
with your friends.
제가 사과했잖아요
But I apologized.
잘못한 게 없어서
더욱 힘들었다고요
And that was hard for me because
I didn't do anything wrong.
쉘리, 네가 어릴 때부터
강연은 충분히 다닌 것 같구나
Shelly, I hung out with you
in enough dusty lecture halls
while you were growing up.
이번에는 관광을 하고 싶어
I want to go sightseeing.
그러니까 팬케익이나 먹고
So why don't you
have some pancakes,
같이 나가자
get dressed and come with us.
갈 생각 없으니
억지 부리지 마세요
I'm not going,
and you can't make me.
그래, 좋은 하루 보내
You're right, I can't.
Have a nice day.
엄마가 생각 바꿀 때까지
계속 서 있을 거에요
Well, I'm going to stand here
until you change your mind.
종일 서 있어야겠네
Well, then you are going
to stand there all day.
베이컨 기름이랑
저쪽으로 미끄러질게요
I'm just gonna take my bacon
grease and slide over there.
엄마한테 버림 받다니
믿을 수 없어요
I can't believe my own
mother is abandoning me.
버림 받다니?
I am not abandoning you.
바구니에 넣어 교회 문앞에
두고 가야 버리는 거지
Sheldon, abandoning you
is leaving you in a basket
on a church doorstep.
로널드 레이건 밀랍인형한테
고맙다고 인사할 거야
I am going to Hollywood and
thank a wax Ronald Reagan
for his service
to our country.
의견이 많이 갈리네요
We appear to be at a crossroads
in our relationship, Mother.
그렇구나
Well, I guess we are.
시럽 가지러 왔어요
Sorry.
Syrup.
그래요, 엄마
All right, Mom.
리플리의 믿거나 말거나
박물관을 방문하시고
When you're at the Ripley's
Believe It Or Not Museum,
세상에서 제일 멋진 아들을
버린 엄마가 전시되어 있다면
if they have an exhibit about a
mother who threw away a chance
to spend the day with the
world's most wonderful son,
사실이니까
믿어도 좋아요
believe it,
because it's true.
아직...
I hadn't...
강연 때문에 시간 버렸어
That lecture was
a waste of time.
초기 우주 확장에 대해
I made more accurate diagrams
어린이방 벽에
더 정확한 그림을 그렸었어
of the expansion of the early
universe on the nursery wall
기저귀 속 내용물로 말이야
with the contents
of my diaper.
(sneezes)
감기 걸렸어?
Are you getting sick?
아니, 이유 없이 노벨상
받은 사람한테 알레르기가 있어
No, I'm just allergic to people
who get Nobel Prizes
for no good reason.
쉘든, 네가 기분이
별로라는 걸 알겠어
Sheldon, is it possible
that your foul mood--
의학 용어로는
성마름이라고도 하지
or, to use the clinical
term, bitchiness--
엄마의 우선 순위에서
밀려서 그러는 거니?
is because your mother
isn't making you a priority?
아니거든,
의학 용어로는 '아님'
No. Or to use the
clinical term, "nuh-uh""
확실해? 모아관계는
영장류 심리학의 기본이야
Are you sure?
The infant-mother pair-bond
is the building block
of primate psychology.
그럼 그렇지
Oh, there it is.
넌 항상 원숭이 타령이야
It always comes back
to monkeys with you.
원숭이, 원숭이, 원숭이
Just monkeys,
monkeys, monkeys.
쉘든, 우리는 동물이야
Sheldon, we're all animals.
네가 어떤 면으로는
특별하기도 한데
And granted, there are aspects
of you that are extraordinary,
감정이랑 관계에서는
but when it comes to
emotions and relationships,
누구나 다 똑같아
you're just like everybody else.
내가 감정적으로
겪는 문제들이
Are you trying to suggest
that my emotional problems
바보랑 같은 수준이라는 거야?
are no different than
those of a stupid person?
어떤 연구에 의하면
Actually, some research
indicates
지적 능력이 낮은 사람들이
감정을 더 잘 다스린대
that by not overthinking,
the less intelligent
handle emotions better.
(sneezes)
감기 걸린 거 아냐?
Sure you're not coming
down with a cold?
그래, 그 흔한 감기
Oh, yes, the common cold.
누구나 다 똑같이 걸리지
Just like everyone else.
네가 좋아할 법하네
You'd love that,
wouldn't you?
여기는 아늑하네
Oh, this one's sweet.
묵주 딸랑이들이 좋아하겠어
You know,
for your rosary rattlers.
묵주 딸랑이가 아니라
가톨릭이라고 불러요
Mrs. Cooper, we say "Catholics""
not "rosary rattlers."
캘리포니아에서는
할 수 있는 얘기가 없구나
My goodness, it's a wonder
you people in California
can talk at all.
최악의 할리우드 투어야
This is like the
worst Hollywood tour ever.
성당을 보고 싶어하시잖아
What are we gonna do?
She wanted to see churches.
여기 와인 있지 않아?
Hey, they have wine
here, don't they?
우리가 믿는 신 중에는
저런 복근 없는데
None of our gods
have abs like that.
유대인 중에 마지막으로
윗몸일으키기를 한 분이셔
Yep, that's the last
Jew who did sit-ups.
결국 저런 꼴이 됐잖아
And look where it got him.
여기 왔으니
모두 기도할까?
Hey, while we're here, why
don't we all do some praying?
교회 분위기 좀 내자
Let's put a little
church in this church.
그래도 되는지...
Oh, I'm not sure we should...
쉬우니까 나만 따라 해
It's easy.
I'll show you how.
주님, 매리 쿠퍼입니다
Lord, Mary Cooper here.
캘리포니아 고모라에서
인사 드려요
Coming to you from
Gomorrah, California.
쉘리라는 축복을 주셔서
감사드립니다
I want to thank you
for the blessing that
is my little Shelly.
성서로 아이를 패고 싶은
욕구를 참게 해주셔서 고마워요
I also want to thank you
for the continued strength
not to coldcock him
with my Bible.
페니, 네 차례다
All right, Penny, your turn.
Okay, um...
Hey, God.
What's up?
전 다 괜찮은데
우리 가족을 위해
Um, I'm good, but, uh, it would
be a big help to my family
동생이 마약 제조를
그만두면 좋겠어요
if you could get my brother
to stop cooking meth.
경찰은 빼주세요
But no cops. Be cool.
이 아이는 이웃을
지나치게 사랑해서 문제에요
She also goes a little overboard
on the "love thy neighbor."
막달라 마리아와 나눴던
대화가 도움이 되겠네요
Could probably use that chat
you had with Mary Magdalene.
레너드, 네 차례야
Leonard, you're up.
유대인, 다음은 너야
Wasserman, you're on deck.
어디 보자
Okay. I don't know...
키 크게 해달라는 건
이미 늦었겠죠
it's probably a little late
to ask you to make me taller.
여자친구랑 잘 되게
도와주면 좋겠어요
Oh, um... if you could help
out with me and my girlfriend.
멀리 인도에 살고 있거든요
She's all the way in India.
That would be great.
들었죠?
여자 문제에요
Hear that? Girl trouble.
우리가 잘못 짐작했나봐요
Turns out we were both wrong
on that front.
넌 어때?
How about you?
전 괜찮아요
Oh, me? No.
Thanks, I'm good.
저는 타버리지만 않으면 돼요
I'm really just trying not
to burst into flames.
라지?
Rajesh?
2킬로만 더 빼고 싶대요
He says he's having trouble
dropping those last five pounds.
여자랑 대화하는 게
더 큰 문제일텐데
Huh, I might have gone with
the talking-to-girls thing.
소원은 하나만 빌어
No, you only get one wish.
우리 둘 좀 봐요
Look at the two of us.
저는 존경받는 물리학자에요
Me, a highly
regarded physicist.
한 세기에 나올까 말까한
명석한 두뇌를 갖고 있죠
The kind of mind that
comes along once,
maybe twice in a generation.
그쪽은 일반인이고요
You, the common man,
하루 일과를 마친
증권 중개인
tired from your labors
as a stockbroker,
청소기 판매원 혹은
구두닦이일 수 있겠네요
or vacuum cleaner salesman,
or bootblack.
그런데 마음 속 깊이 보면
But deep down inside...
붕어빵처럼 비슷하대요
apparently we're just
two peas in a pod.
그쪽은 일반 붕어빵
A regular pea,
저는 한 세기에
나올까 말까한
and the kind of pea
that comes along once,
특별한 붕어빵이죠
maybe twice in a generation.
(thunder booms)
비 오네요
Rain.
모두에 해당되는 거죠
Another great equalizer.
훌륭한 머리도 비에 젖고
Falling on the head
of the brilliant
평범한 머리도 마찬가지에요
and the unremarkable alike.
잘났군요
Smarty-pants.
냄새가 너무 좋아요
Oh, Mrs. Cooper,
it smells so good.
적어두거라
You take notes, darlin'.
남자를 얻는 방법은
녹인 치즈랑
The real way to get a man
is with melted cheese
버섯 크림 스프야
and cream of mushroom soup.
나이 50에 죽겠지만
진정한 사랑을 받을 거야
He'll die at 50 but
his love will be true.
새 휴지가 필요해
I need a tissue.
This one got wet.
여기
Here.
고마워,
오늘 뭔가 배웠어
Thank you. Yeah, I've
learned something today.
우리는 여러 면에서 같아
You and I, in so many ways,
지능이나 그런 중요한 것을
제외하면 말이야
other than intelligence and
what counts, we're the same.
(sneezes)
아가야, 어디 아프니?
Sweetheart, are you sick?
지금 상태가 아픈 게 아니라면
더 살고 싶지 않아요
I hope so, because if this is
well, life isn't worth living.
이런, 열이 너무 심하네
Oh, sugarpie,
you are burning up.
자, 침대로 가자
- We've got to get you to bed.
- Okay.
엄마가 돌봐줄게, 아가야
Don't worry. Mama's here
to take care of her baby.
아가만 돌봐주는 거 맞죠?
And just to be clear,
only her baby
다른 사람들은 빼고요
and not these other people.
물론이지
Of course.
꿀차랑 껍질 잘라 낸
토스트 먹어도 돼요?
Can I have tea with honey and
toast with the crust cut off?
뭐든 먹어도 되지
You can have
whatever you want.
엄마가 최고예요
Thanks, Mom.
You're the best.
전에 로션 발라줄 때는
Boy, last time I put
VapoRub on you,
가슴에 털이 없었는데
you didn't have hair
on your chest.
작년에 생겼어요
I know, it filled in last year.
이번에는 같이
시간을 못 보냈어요
I didn't get to spend a lot of
time with you on this visit.
그게 누구 잘못이지?
And whose fault was that?
엄마 잘못이요
Yours.
쉘리, 넌 이제 8살이 아냐
Shelly, you're not eight
years old anymore.
전이랑 달라져야지
We have to have
a different relationship.
아니요
No, we don't.
지금까지 좋았잖아요
The one we have
works great.
얘야, 넌 이제 성인이야
Sweetheart, you are a grown man.
새로운 종일 수도 있어요
Or maybe I'm part of
a new species,
몇 백살까지 사는 생물이면
that lives for
hundreds of years,
지금은 애기나 마찬가지고요
which means I'm still
basically a toddler.
휴스턴에 데려갔어야 하는데
Oh, I so should have
taken you to Houston.
Soft Kitty 안 불러주실 건가요?
Does this mean you're not
going to sing "Soft Kitty"?
그건 항상 불러주는 거지
No, I will always
sing you "Soft Kitty."
♪ Soft kitty, warm kitty ♪
♪ Little ball of fur... ♪
오븐에서 파이
꺼내야 하지 않나요?
Mrs. Cooper, were we supposed to
take that pie out of the oven?
나가
Get out!
이런 버릇없이
Well, that was rude.
레너드도 그럴 생각은
아니였을 거에요
Well, I know,
but he means well.
노래 불러줘요
Sing.
♪ Happy kitty, sleepy kitty... ♪
지금 뭐하시는 거에요?
What are you trying
to pull, Mom?
처음부터 해야죠
From the top.
이런 게 문제라고요
This is what I'm talking about.
♪ Soft kitty, warm kitty,
little ball of fur... ♪
공대언니 블로그
http://tbbt.tistory.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==